WADIH OJEIL

Orlando, FL 32828

Phone: (407)463-6548 | Email: wadih.ojeil@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u>: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wadih-ojeil/ | Github: https://github.com/wojeil | Portfolio: https://wojeil.github.io/my-portfolio-with-react

SUMMARY

Full stack developer and a former Deputy Sheriff with experience and passion in front and back end development. A deep knowledge in Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, MongoDb, IndexDb, PWA, Node.js, JQuery, REACT, Bootstrap and Bulma Framework. Adept at taking challenges and solving problems with demonstrated leadership through team building and people skills. Highly trained to produce results in stressful situations and take necessary actions required to complete tasks. Passion to create something that people interact with, use, touch and love in their daily life through coding and building new technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS.

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JS, MySQL, MongoDb.

Technologies: Node.js, REACT.js, Bootstrap, Bulma, JQuery, Mongoose ORM, API's. **Languages:** English(Native), French(Native), Arabic(Native), Spanish(Limited Working).

PROJECTS

Employee Tracker | https://github.com/wojeil/Employee_Tracker | Fork and Run Node

- **Summary:** Full CRUD prompt-based node application that helps the User create his/her own employee database dynamically via JS in MySQL.
- **Core responsibilities:** To create and deliver a node application that can help a business owner keep track of his employees, departments, roles and salaries within the due date.
- Tools and languages: Node.js, Inquirer.js, Console-Table-Printer, Asciiart-Logo, MySQL and JS.

NoteTaker|https://github.com/wojeil/Note_Taker|https://mighty-sea-99609.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Full CRUD application that allows User to save, update and delete notes.
- **Core responsibilities:** To create and deliver an application with Express.js within the given due date.
- Tools and languages: Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, JS.

The HUB | https://github.com/wojeil/HUB | https://gentle-sea-35926.herokuapp.com/

- **Summary:** MERN application that enhances communication and time-management between admins and their Users. Best applied for the workplace environment and could be applied with friends of common interest.
- Core responsibilities: As Project Manager assigned and managed tasks through GitHub Kanban Board. Designed and created both dashboard pages with Front-End and Delete with Back-End CRUD. Designed and created weekly planner and planner search page with Front-End CRUD and minor Back-End fixes. Worked with my team to conduct wireframes for all pages

including DB set-up with Mongoose ORM through Robo3t. Worked and cooperated with my team to complete the application functions by the due date.

• **Tools and languages:** BootStrap, Mongoose ORM, Express.js, REACT, Node.js, Passport.js, Axios, JSX, HTML5, CSS3, JS.

EXPERIENCE

Deputy Sheriff 07/2016 - 01/2020 **Orange County Sheriff's Office** Orlando, FL

- Prepare formal reports and general investigation for criminal prosecution.
- Write and execute search warrants. Patrol and testify in criminal trials. Process and catalog evidence.
- Adapt to different environments. Manage/Triage workload. Apply informed decisions without direct supervision.
- Protect and Serve my Community.

Key Accomplishments:

- Entrusted with Ride A Longs and two UCF interns that have recently been hired by the agency.
- Lead in a successful narcotics search warrant with no prior experience.
- Advanced Training Certificate Violent Crimes Investigator Training Course (40hr).
- Certificate of Compliance Law Enforcement Officers (770 Hours).

Guest Service Associate 10/2012 – 07/2016

Racetrac Petroleum

Orlando, FL

- Ring up guests on cash register and balance cash and inventory transactions.
- Resolve guest complaints.
- Update prices and post new signage to reflect monthly promotions and sales opportunities.
- All keep a positive attitude.

Key Accomplishments:

- Learned how to communicate with multiple people from different cultures and backgrounds.
- Upsold many guests with promotional products that helped store increase profits.

Student Intern 01/2015 – 04/2015 United States Postal Inspection Service Orlando, FL

- Shadow special agents and assist them when solving cases.
- Sort evidence data in spreadsheets
- Screen incoming mail through USPS.

Key Accomplishments:

- Received a Certificate of Appreciation.
- Earned university credits.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate:University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Security Management Certification: University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL A series of criminal justices credit courses including Security Management, Risk Management in CJ and private sector.

Bachelor of Science in Criminal Justice: University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL Member of Tau Sigma (UCF Transfer Student Honors), Alpha Phi Sigma (Criminal Justice Honors) and Lambda Alpha Epsilon (Criminal Justice Club).

Associate of Arts in General Studies: Valencia College, Orlando, FL

Associate of Arts in General Studies: American University of Beirut, Beirut, Lebanon Completed 18 college credits and transferred to Valencia due to country's poor political situation.